Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/pradipnichite (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Generative Al

ChatGPT

Machine Learning

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Deep Learning Specialization

Honors-Awards

Quarterly Award Winner Winner at HackIQ 2018 hackathon, MIQ

Pradip Nichite

Top Rated Plus - NLP Freelancer | Custom NLP Solutions | GPT-4 | Al Demos

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

Summary

I'm a Top Rated Plus NLP freelancer on Upwork with over \$100K in earnings and a 100% Job Success rate. This journey began in 2022 after years of enriching experience in the field of Data Science.

Starting my career in 2013 as a Software Developer focusing on backend and API development, I soon pursued my interest in Data Science by earning my M.Tech in IT from IIIT Bangalore, specializing in Data Science (2016 - 2018).

Upon graduation, I carved out a path in the industry as a Data Scientist at MiQ (2018 - 2020) and later ascended to the role of Lead Data Scientist at Oracle (2020 - 2022).

Inspired by my freelancing success, I founded FutureSmart AI in September 2022. We provide custom AI solutions for clients using the latest models and techniques in NLP.

In addition, I run Al Demos, a platform aimed at educating people about the latest Al tools through engaging video demonstrations.

My technical toolbox encompasses:

Languages: Python, JavaScript, SQL.

ML Libraries: PyTorch, Transformers, LangChain.

Specialties: Semantic Search, Sentence Transformers, Vector

Databases.

Web Frameworks: FastAPI, Streamlit, Anvil.

In the fast-evolving landscape of AI, FutureSmart AI and I stand at the forefront, delivering cutting-edge, custom NLP solutions to clients across various industries. Upwork Profile: https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~014fdabc6436bf9bd4?viewMode=1

Experience

Upwork

Freelance Data Scientist

February 2022 - Present (1 year 6 months)

Link: https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~014fdabc6436bf9bd4?viewMode=1

Successfully Completed Projects:

- 1. Text Classification, Document Classification
- 2. Sentiment Analysis, Aspect Based Sentiment Analysis
- 3. Custom Named Entity Recognition
- 4. Question Answering System
- 5. Topic Modeling
- 6. Fine-tuning GPT-3

FutureSmart Al

Founder & Lead Data Scientist

February 2022 - Present (1 year 6 months)

Building Custom Natural Language Processing Solutions.

Oracle

2 years 1 month

Tech Lead - Data Science

September 2021 - February 2022 (6 months)

Machine Learning Solutions for Oracle Cloud Products.

Data Science Mentor

July 2021 - February 2022 (8 months)

Helping Transition Internal Employees To Data Science Team

Senior Data Scientist

February 2020 - December 2021 (1 year 11 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

Email (text) Classification and Topic Modeling for identifying conflicts (Risks) during project collaboration.

Python, Spacy, Genism, Xgboost, Pytorch. NLP, Deep Learning, MLOps, Docker.

Project Collaboration Network Analysis networkx, Python, d3 js, Javascript

upGrad

10 months

Subject Matter Expert September 2021 - November 2021 (3 months)

Collaborated with the Learning Experience Department for developing curriculum for MLOPs

Data Science Coach & Mentor February 2021 - August 2021 (7 months)

MiQ

2 years

Data Scientist

July 2018 - December 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Worked on AdTech data products that optimizes ad spends to achieve better ROI on digital advertising campaigns. Product uses 10 TB+ data every day to build models for 500+ campaigns.

Product got featured in Analytics India Magazine's Top Data Science Products Build in India.

https://analyticsindiamag.com/top-data-science-products-build-in-india-2020/

Roles and Responsibilities

- ♦ Improving existing model performance by tuning hyperparameters.
- ◆ Building and maintaining scalable feature engineering pipelines using Spark, Hive.
- ◆ Automating end to end data pipeline using Jenkins and Databricks jobs.
- ◆ Data Analysis for understanding product performance and the impact of the new feature release.
- ♦ Optimize existing code and make it scalable and robust

Data Science Intern
January 2018 - June 2018 (6 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

♦ Build an Automated Machine Learning (AutoML) system, a distributed service that selects the best machine learning model with automatically tunned hyperparameter for the given dataset.

Roles and Responsibilities

- ◆ Research and Develop a machine learning prototype using open source technologies.
- ♦ Work closely with the Engineering team to productionize prototype.
- ◆ Automate the process using Jenkins, AWS and make it available to endusers.
- ◆ Extend the functionality of existing open-source libraries

Technologies: Python, Apache Spark, Skelarn, AWS, Bayesian Optimization.

The Horizon Technologies Senior Software Developer July 2015 - June 2016 (1 year) Mumbai Area, India

- -- Developed online school management system.
- -- Developed Rest API using Python Flask.

https://horizontech.in/

Aeon IT Solutions Software Developer November 2014 - July 2015 (9 months)

Mumbai Area, India

- -- Worked on Development of Shopping portal.
- -- Used Facebook API to the build custom dashboard for marketing campaigns.

https://aeondigital.in/

Technologies: PHP,MySQL,Javascript

The Horizon Technologies Software Developer July 2013 - October 2014 (1 year 4 months) Mumbai Area, India

- -- Developed a custom ERP system using the PHP framework for an online education company.
- -- Build custom Web applications using WordPress CMS.

https://horizontech.in/

Education

International Institute of Information Technology – Bangalore Master of Technology - MTech, Data Science · (2016 - 2018)

Dr.Babasaheb Ambedkar Technological University, Lonere - Raigad Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Information Technology (2009 - 2013)

G.V.Khade Vidyalaya Shahapur,Thane,Maharashtra Science (2004 - 2009)